we have our next speaker bhagavatas
gupta
he is managing director and ceo of icici
lombard general insurance company
limited
it's the largest private sector general
insurance company
in india
he has held key leadership positions in
diverse business areas in the icici
group
including project finance corporate
banking e-commerce and technology
management
internet international banking and life
insurances so now
we would like him to get a forward
decision
[Music]
thank you prasad and thank you iit for
giving us this opportunity to present
something about what we are doing uh in
the technology space in
insurance uh you know this is a bunch of
very smart engineers i am really a
business person but what i try to do is
contextualizing contextualize how we are
trying to use
some of these cutting-edge technologies
to solve business problems
i think the previous speaker so if you
can just start with the uh
the first light so as i said you know
i'll focus on
uh some of the areas that we are using
uh technology to solve business problems
usually using uh
iot's ai ml et cetera advanced analytics
i think the previous speaker talked uh
you know there's one slide that i saw
which is very very appropriate
where she talked about how large
enterprises
which do not adopt and do not adapt to
the new ways of working
do not survive for the long term and
equally true is that the ones that do
uh you know really stay ahead and build
a big lead
with the rest so uh you know while we
are not a tech company but that's the
attempt that we are making in at isis
now this is something that
you know all of you would be you know
fully aware of right
uh the the prevalence of
uh you know some of these solutions in
our lives so if you see
what's happening in each of this i mean
and i don't need to explain any of this
to you
but what let's say alexa uses uh
you know the nlp to you know convert
speech to text and then look at
texts with pro appropriate context
enable geo tagging to
give you and then do a search on
tomorrow's weather to give you an answer
to a question
of what is the weather like tomorrow or
what
google does in again using some of the
same tools
to get device data from multiple
consumers again
using an optimization algorithm to tell
you which is the best route to take
or for example facebook's you know deep
learning vision algorithm which
uh uses image based uh you know data
image data and
tags friends or what amazon uses uh
which is their you know item to item
uh collaborative filtering algorithm to
give you give you recommendations based
on
your you know understanding you as a
consumer and the type of books that
you've read
and you know similar to what others do
so this is something that is there in
all of our lives we are experiencing it
every single day
and one of the things that we believe
has been tremendously transformative
is you know this whole uh lockdown
effect that we've had across the globe
and we are seeing a digital
transformation being accelerated even
further some of these things were
happening
as we you know all know but our belief
is that this is getting transformed
at an even faster pace some of the most
uh
in a sense traditional areas i mean for
five six thousand years
human beings have learned in you know
face-to-face environment you know the
from the guru shisha days to
classrooms where teacher would stand up
and deliver uh you know
your training and and teaching that's
also getting uh completely
transformed you know largely forced you
know due to the lockdown
but even otherwise in terms of the
benefits of some of these uh
you know technologies that are that we
are seeing today and the and the
experience that we've had in this last
you know eight nine months
tells us that some of these things will
be here to stay and you know just a fun
fact
for all of you uh interested in you know
getting into the startup
area uh in the last few years we've had
in india
about four thousand eight tech startups
and the total
funding that they've got you know has
been uh you know
close to about two billion dollars so
it's not a small
sector at all even though as i said
traditionally this is not something that
people believed would happen so if you
go to the next slide
yeah i think i've covered this go to the
next slide please yeah so uh if you look
at
what's happening in terms of some of the
other areas
uh when we look at the changes that is
happening driven by
uh you know these new technologies and
how it's transforming
problems that we never thought would be
solvable uh you know
even 10 years back so if you look at the
changes that are happening on the ground
uh just an example of this swedish
company which
launched a robotic lawn mowing you know
a robotic lawn mowing system now lawn
mowing you know may be space seemed very
simple for a human being but for a robot
is very very complicated and this is a
machine that
actually mows lawns where with even at
about 70 degree incline
which is an incline where a skier
doesn't ski down he
just say does the cliff jump so it's
even at that level this is a
you know robo which is you know very
very effective and by the way
the business that this business company
does is not small
this company is a five billion billion
dollar company and roughly about
35 percent of their revenues come from
the sales of these
robotic lawn mowers the next slide
please
so similarly as we are seeing the
underground you know even on the air
right
so if you uh you know some of you would
be aware
the uh first drone based pisa delivery
was done
to a couple um in new zealand
back in the year 2016 uh where domino's
delivered
you know peripery pizza to this couple
about 20 miles
from you know away from auckland so so
the changes that we are seeing is
happening
not only in uh on the ground but also
you know on air if you can go to the
next slide please
so the question then is why should
insurance be left behind
now i don't know how much uh any one of
you know about insurance
or the history of insurance insurance
industry is
possibly the first industry which used
data science
in our industry we don't call them data
scientists traditionally we used to call
them actuarians
actuaries and you know if you go back to
history uh
the first solution to a problem
that any industry used when they used
probability and statistics and data
science
was to solve for uh the
the pension um you know payout for
widows in scotland
so that is the the that is the genesis
of uh the
uh you know pension the life sciences
the life insurance industry and
similarly for non-life
there's been a lot of data and analytics
that has been used over the years
to predict uh the losses and figure out
whether
the premium that we charge is adequate
or not
so this has been a traditional industry
which has used data science but
in the last maybe 50-60 years it's not
an industry that seemed to be
you know at the cutting edge when it
comes to leveraging technology
and and you know as we speak even today
the
impression from outside is uh is this
industry using enough uh
you know data and analytics to solve uh
some of the
key customer problems particularly using
the new age technologies that that we
you know we talked about so i'll just uh
you know
start with a small video about some of
the things that we are doing at iceland
if you can just start play the video
please
[Music]
accidents are always associated with
stress and insurance claims can be time
consuming
but not anymore i've just damaged my
bumper
but the claims process is no longer
tedious
i'm using this new ai app to upload
pictures for my insurance claim
it gives an accurate cost within seconds
now i feel more prepared and confident
when i go to the service center
last year when i had a cracked
windshield i had to take my car to the
service center and wait in line
then the engineer reviewed the damage
and estimated costs manually
later the insurance inspector arrived to
approve the cost
and only then could i go ahead with the
repairs
the damage inspection process took a
total of two to three days
[Music]
by using the app i can take my car for
repair within a few minutes
so this is a capability that uh our
you know in-house data scientist team uh
you know created
they've been working on this for a good
you know two to three years now
and you know the challenge that that i'm
sure all of you understand better than
that and they're better than me was um
you know really
you know can be broken down to multiple
levels starting with
um looking at the quality of image i
mean at times
uh you know the the first basic problem
is the quality of the image
the orientation of the camera you have
to guide the customer
through that process or flip it around
identification of the damaged part you
know you know the car that we are
looking at
what which vehicle is this uh then once
you've done that
then identification of the damage type
you know whether it's a dent or a
scratch or a crack
uh the extent of damage and the linkage
to the relevant part is it a front
bumper or a windshield or
you know something else uh then a
decision whether this can be repaired is
it a big enough
you know is it is it a large damage that
needs repairing or can it be uh
that can that needs a replacement or can
it be repaired that's another
you know decision that we have to take
and then you know figure out what is the
appropriate cost that we have to pay for
so this is something that we uh the part
of the solution we've
already launched for customers where we
are identifying the
damage and allowing some of the other
processes to go through
and the actual repair estimate is now
begin being given to our
claims engineers claims managers uh to
optimize and you know come to the right
decision
so this is something that we are already
doing as a company based on the work
that our data scientist teams have
uh you know been you know working on for
the last couple of years
if you can turn to the next slide
yeah so in terms of the other areas you
know insurance
you know in general insurance we do
multiple types of insurance motor
insurance is one of them
the second big part of our business is
health insurance and what happens in
health insurance is
uh you pay a small premium and you know
you hope that you don't fall sick but
unfortunately if you do you go to a
hospital
in the hospital to start treatment they
need authorization from the insurance
company
to validate whether the insurance policy
is correct whether these
you know treatment costs are covered so
what they do is they
you know typically fax some case papers
and you know documents etc to
the insurance company doctors in the
insurance company looks at
you know all the papers and then gives
an authorization to start the treatment
traditionally this process takes you
know one two three four hours in certain
cases
for us you know typically it would take
about an hour
and that's a process that now we've
converted completely in you know using a
uh you know a deep learning solution
where
the facts in you know document that
comes in is uh
digitized using an icr ocr
techniques the ml algol algorithm looks
at past data
and authorizes uh the treatment if the
treatment has to be authorized
if the engine philly believes that it
shouldn't be authorized
then it uh you know uh gets transferred
to a
actual doctor and the doctor then takes
the final uh you know judgment call
and through that process we are also
training the engine to become better and
better
so what used to take as i said you know
an hour or a bit more
now gets done in 90 seconds and
obviously it frees up our
doctor's time to do more uh value-added
work in terms of
you know portfolio analytics etc
if you go to the next next slide please
yeah so if you see some of the other
areas that
you know some of these technologies
particularly iot i talked about
there's a lot of media talk and a lot of
interest
uh in terms of using telematics for uh
motor insurance
now that's something that you know
that's very common well-known you know a
lot of companies are trying it
we as a company are doing the same thing
with uh you know as an experiment
we've actually been able to build uh
driver
scores in terms of driving quality
scores based on the data that we
get from the overdue devices the iot
devices fixed on the car
and using that data we've built an
algorithm to figure out the
you know the quality of driving and
again against that we've correlated the
experience of claims
and accordingly we can actually use the
data to uh price
uh premium going ahead once some of this
is uh you know regulatory allowed in
india some experimentation has happened
already in india
but the formal launch of these products
are pending but in the meantime there is
another uh you know business use case
that we feel is even more powerful
which is for corporates we also ensure
their
the supply chain right when goods are
transiting from one part of the country
to another
if any damage happens that's something
that insurance companies pay for
and what we've done just to give you a
couple of examples is let's say
for of you know today we are talking
about the vaccine right it has to go
through you know it has to use a cold
you know change cold supply chain uh
refrigerator cargos etc
so this is something that anyway
pharmacy industries has been doing
maybe at a lower level of temperature
you know compared to the temperature
that we are talking about for vaccine
but cold chain is something that is
common in pharmacy industry so
with one of our you know corporate
clients what we've done is using an iot
device to track the
uh track the entire supply chain now
what happens in india i mean these are
the real ground level
you know issues that you have to uh
solve for uh what happens in india
is that a lot of times uh you know the
drivers
optimize or conserve uh you know the
full you know they're incentivized to
conserve fuel so
at times they switch off the uh
refrigeration
unit to save on full and we get
immediately triggered and if that
happens the cargo can
can be damaged so some of these devices
that we have gives us an automatic
trigger
and we call out to the driver you know
and ask him why has it switched off the
uh the refrigerant unit so some of these
solutions are not only helping in
you know prevent losses but it's also
being expanded to give uh
almost a logistic solution to some of
our you know clients one
large metal company we have kind of
build a just-in-time
uh you know inventory tracking system
using some of these capabilities
and not only using gps but even uh you
know triangulation of
the you know the the the the the towers
using the sme
sms data so these are some of the things
that we've done if you if you can go to
the last slide
so again you know going back to a
example for health underwriting
um i gave an example of the claims what
happens when we uh
when a claim happens but equally when we
uh
issue a policy we do what is known as
underwriting we
we ask questions of an individual and uh
you know to get a status of the
uh you know of how you know is his
health status in a sense
traditionally doctors would call and ask
questions uh again that's something that
we've now been able to uh you know
convert using and
uh you know auto you know a voice bot
and an nlp
engine which converts the you know the
speech into text
again you know there's an algorithm
which looks at the text and the context
and then
uh using their algorithm we decide
whether this cases uh
needs uh you know human doctor to check
or
will it make or we make it straight
through for the customer to get
the policy smoothly so these are some of
the examples of
uh work that we are doing at ics alone
but within our teams as also in
partnership with some of the uh
ecosystem that has come up in india uh
which
i'm sure a lot of you would be aware of
and and you have friends in
uh but clearly as a company this has
been a big focus for us
and this is not restricted to india i
mean i'm talking about you know
what we are doing in india but globally
if you go to some of the
uh some of the accelerator programs or
incubation centers you'll see a lot of
activity on the
inshore tech side and in fact in some of
the places inshore tech is probably
becoming bigger than uh fintech
and there's been a lot of innovation
that has been happening globally in this
space
uh including new startups that have uh
you know come forth
uh there's one company which if you're
tracking the space you'll
you would have heard about this is one
of the most successful ipos
in this year in 2020 a company called
lemonade which started
just in 2017 and they've
completely you know they're trying to
completely transform that the way uh
insurance is experienced by their
customers they're focused on
one type of insurance in in in u.s it's
called renters insurance
so when you rent a property the
insurance that you have to buy uh
it's similar to home insurance but you
know slightly lower uh you know scale
and if you go to the next slide there's
a video that i wanted to share with you
so if you can just play the video please
[Music]
oh
so obviously this is a completely af
first company everything that you saw
happening on the mobile
screen was happening without any human
intervention even that video that you
saw the customer
uh you know video of the customer being
recorded there is an engine behind uh
based on the way she's uh explaining her
claim
it can figure out the probability of a
you know fraud because that's something
that the insurance industry have to work
very hard to prevent
because if fraud increases the premium
increases for the genuine customers
that's not something we want so
everything is really done
using some of these uh you know as i
said it's an afl first company all of
this is using
artificial intelligence
so that's what i wanted to talk about in
terms of the
adoption of technology and the way this
technology is transforming
insurance not only in india but across
the world
if you go to the next slide this is
you know a similar point that i wanted
to make right that i made at the
beginning
you know our belief is that uh if you
don't uh
disrupt yourself uh you'll get disrupted
and i think the
you know the best companies uh in every
uh you know business
as also an insurance is looking at how
do we how do we stay ahead of the curve
in terms of adopting uh some of these
tools and
adapting our you know adapting to these
new environment and and
adopting these tools so and lastly
again you know as i said i don't want to
use this as a plug but any one of you
who is really interested
in you showed in your presentation
we can claim insurance by taking
pictures
of the parts which are damaged or some
things like that
so how is privacy taken into account in
such cases
look at the end of the day we already
have a relationship with you
right so when you come when it comes to
privacy we are not doing something that
you don't give us an authorization to do
uh number one
and you know if you think about what it
does is
changes a physical process into a more
convenient digital process let me
explain this so in the past what would
you do is that
like can you tell like how the pandemic
has
affect your company and the insurance
center in general
look so uh when it comes to uh the way
the sun
is created greater awareness
that uh unpredictable events happen
uh which we are not in control of and
that's what insurance is about right
so all of us hope that you know we won't
have a car accident but
accidents do happen all of us hope that
we don't fall sick but unfortunately
people do fall sick
we all hope that there won't be a fire
in my factory but it so happens that
they do happen so
you know none of us want any of this to
happen as an insurance company also we
don't want you to fall sick
right so in the sense that possible
because of some of these tools so diy
contactless services i mean just to give
you an example of this
video inspection that i'm talking about
uh our numbers
or let's say the claim authorization on
the motorcycle on the health side our
numbers which was roughly about the high
20s as the total percentage of claims
that are going through that process has
gone to about
uh more than 60 now so that's the ramp
up that we've seen in a matter of
six seven months so it's been a
tremendously transformative
event for everyone and including for
insurance
uh yeah there was also a question
like can you tell like oh how
is the digitalization in india
compared to the digitalization in the
developed countries
so like what are the strengths and
weaknesses in both conditions
look one of the things that you know let
me start with an example that
uh that i shared in the presentation so
this entire
uh you know image ai solution that we
developed in-house to solve for this
claim assessment problem on the motor
side
we initially uh looked at what was
happening in the world
uh there was a global you know start-up
which was looking at this solving this
problem they were working with some
american companies they had come to
india to look for
look to see if they could solve the same
problem for their jv partner in india
realized that the jv partner was too
small then they came to us
in the meantime they had some problems
i'm not sure what happened but
they decided not to proceed with the
indian market
in the meantime you know we had started
working on this in any case ourselves
and we said we don't need any uh you
know maybe we can do this ourselves
uh and and we build this uh piece so in
a sense some of these tools are
uh possible for anyone to create one of
the big advantages that we have is we
have
a much larger scope as a country
at two levels one we have more data
period i mean you know we are 1.38
a billion and you know if you've
organized your data well you've kind of
tagged it well you've
stored it in the past you have a lot
more data than because the volumes that
we deal with in india is much much
higher secondly this is potentially
creating an opportunity for us to
leapfrog you know if you look at health
uh particularly health
tech or you know health insurance of
health care um
we have an opportunity of using this uh
you know these capabilities of these
technologies to leapfrog
uh and become a much more effort digital
health uh you know
ecosystem in india than what the western
world would be
simply because there is very strong
entrance legacy systems that have
already built in
so breaking that may take uh take some
time here you are almost
solving a problem that i mean you know
healthcare is not even available to half
the you know populations you can solve
it
using the fact that we have more uh you
know data points
as also the fact that we can do it much
more you know cheaply
at a low cost and solve a problem that
is not being you know even addressed
today
by any other solution but to answer your
question of
you know as of now we see uh you know
the real
uh cutting-edge work happening in china
uh and thereafter to some extent in in
us
but uh you know really the guys who are
leading this pieces
uh so like a personality question
so what appealed to you in this
insurance uh
like background and also like where do
you see
this part in some like five years
down the line what
uh what excites me personally about
insurance
look uh you know uh one of the things
that i realized coming into insurance i
have been you know when i came out of my
business school i
joined icc and that was a banking role
uh but
came into general insurance about 11
years back almost 12 years now
in isis in 2009 one of the things that i
uh
really enjoy about this industry is that
if you're an engineer
there is a lot more connect to your core
engineering in this industry i mean some
of the things that i talked about
in terms of using technology to solve
problems
the opportunity in our industry is
tremendous
you know in terms of you know solving
risk problems for customers
using technology uh but even at a basic
level
uh if you are an uh you know mechanical
engineer which i am
i've forgotten my mechanical injury
honestly but uh
you know if you're an automobile
engineer uh your you know the
depth of understanding that you need um
to be a good
claim you know service provider you know
is a deeper understanding of the
you know the engineering of the
automobiles uh because you really need
to understand the
uh the components the parts the suburbs
our sub assemblies and you know figure
out
uh you know whether you can repair this
and there is some amount of engineering
understanding of engineering there so
there is a lot of technical input
so it's a this is a lot more a lot more
of a
techno financial you know industry
rather than a pure financial industry
so that's one thing that i find it very
exciting to be in this industry
uh and plus you know the way to the
scope to use technology to solve
customer problem here is tremendous uh
honestly speaking
and the other question about you know
where do we see uh
you know this five years later look our
belief is that among financial services
an industry that i today understand
because i've been in most part of the
financial services
this industry probably has the longest
runway of growth because today it is
still one of the it's uh
you know it's in terms of penetration
it's way you know below
behind the curve and this is natural
because what happens when as a society
goes through
uh you know its journey of affluence um
data has shown that when per capita
income of a country reaches about two
thousand dollars
the the insurance penetration starts
picking up it's a
it's a s-shaped curve it's kind of slow
initially then once it cuts
crosses two thousand dollars it rapidly
increases and then plateaus after a
point in life
and if you look and if you think about
it from a consumer level
it is natural because when you start
becoming a bit more when you have some
spare
uh you know money you start thinking of
saving it
or you then think of buying an asset
maybe a you know
car and then a home and once you do all
of that then you think of protecting it
so it's a stage of evolution of any
every industry and our industry in that
sense has a longer runway of growth
is the belief that i have
thank you very much sir for the session
it was really
wonderful interacting with you and like
everyone i hope
enjoyed and got much info about icici
thank you so much thank you for having
me here
you